# ALEKSANDR MIRLENKO

<u>aleksandr.mirlenko@ru.abb.com</u> <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/mirlenko/</u>

+79111998326

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Automation Engineer with Data Analytics and Machine Learning skills willing to take a new role as a Digitalization Specialist

### DATA ANALYSIS AND MACHINE LEARNING TRAINING

Link to projects and certificates: <a href="https://github.com/Mirlenko">https://github.com/Mirlenko</a>

Apr. 2020 – present (Online Courses)

- Machine Learning and Data Analysis Specialization (6 courses by Moscow Institute of Physics and Technology & Yandex);
- Machine Learning (Stanford University);
- Deep Learning (Moscow Institute of Physics and Technology);
- SQL for Data Science (University of California).

# **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

#### **Automation Project Engineer, ABB**

Jan. 2019 – Present (Kaliningrad, Russia & Ostrava, Czech Republic)

For Marine & Ports (Global 1 Cruise Vessel):

- Developed and tested 800xA based control software using functional design specifications and P&ID;
- designed and configured HMI graphics, wrote function description.

For Process Industries:

- Developed and configured software and HMI for Data Center (Modiin, Israel);
- upgraded the Pulp & Paper plant HMI graphics (the SAICA project, Spain).

#### **Automation Project Engineer, System-Service**

Oct. 2017 – Dec. 2018 (Saint Petersburg, Russia)

- Developed, analyzed and reviewed PLC (Siemens Simatic) and SCADA programs (WinCC, TIA Portal) for Gas Compressing Units;
- conduct Startup and Commissioning at the Boosting Compressor Station (Zapolyarnaya gas condensate field beyond the Arctic Circle).

#### Master's Thesis Position, School of Energy Systems, LUT

Jan. 2017 – Aug. 2017 (Lappeenranta, Finland)

- Research and design of Electrically Excited Synchronous Motor control system in Matlab Simulink;
- the project results are presented in the Master's Thesis 'Control of EESM in the field weakening range'.

# **EDUCATION**

# Lappeenranta University of Technology (LUT), Finland Saint Petersburg Electrotechnical University 'LETI', Russia

Master of Science, Electrical Engineering, Aug. 2017

Due to Double Degree program, I hold master's degrees from both Universities.

Saint Petersburg Electrotechnical University 'LETI', Russia

Bachelor of Science, Electrical Engineering, Jul. 2015

# **SKILLS & LANGUAGES**

Data Analysis	<b>PLC</b> programming	Python	Russian - Native
Machine Learning	HMI & SCADA	pandas & numpy scipy & statsmodels	English - Proficient
Deep Learning	Commissioning	matplotlib & seaborn scikit-learn tensorflow & keras	Finnish – Basic
		SQL	
		Embedded C	
		Matlab	